

## Patricia McPhee

TECHNICAL WRITER
CONTENT DEVELOPER
UX WRITER

Broomfield, CO hi@patriciamcphee.com www.patriciamcphee.work

### **About Me**

I have 25 years of experience creating scenario and goal-based content to help IT professionals achieve more with technology. I'm passionate about bringing stale or unusable content back to life by taking the guesswork out of complex technical content.

### **Education**

10/2010 - 05/2012 **Kaplan University** BS in Health Science

02/1999 – 04/2001 DeVry University - Denver

AS Computer Systems (networking and telecommunications)

## **Work Experience**

05/2020 - Pres.

# **Content Developer, Contractor Microsoft/Kforce**

Work collaboratively with the Azure VMware Solution core engineering and UX Research teams to develop scenario and goal-based content. Write and edit UX microcopy and UI strings. Conduct content audits of existing content to identify areas for improvement. Use qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2019 - 06/2021

#### Freelance

- Extreme Networks (2020 2021) Reviewed and edited network hardware content for the FIPS program.
- Netdata (2020) Wrote product content for a Linux server performance tool.
- **ZPE Systems (2019-2020)** Wrote a marketing campaign eBook. Wrote video scripts, provided the voiceover, and produced how-to videos.
- Wax.io (2019) Contributed to blockchain blog articles.

03/2019 - 06/2019 **Technical Writer II** LivePerson

Wrote SDK and API guides for mobile messaging app.

01/2018 - 01/2019 **Technical Writer II** Microsoft

Worked collaboratively with the Microsoft Edge and Windows networking core teams. Wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings. Conducted content audits to identify areas for potential improvement. Used qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2017 - 12/2017 **Technical Writer, Contractor** Oculus/Facebook

Developed internal cross-functional workflows and process documentation for a virtual reality R&D environment.

08/2016 - 05/2017 **Software Technical Writer** GE Healthcare

Worked collaboratively with customers and support to update the outdated installation and upgrade guides. The rework resulted in more successful upgrades and reduced customer support calls.



### **Skills**

**Technical Writing** 

Content Strategy

**UX/UI** Writing

Information Architecture

Project Management

Instructional Design

DITA/oXygen

Markdown

Git/GitHub

Agile/Jira/Azure DevOps

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Premiere Pro

Video Production

Figma/Adobe UX

Jekyll (static site generator)

## **Work Experience (cont'd)**

09/2015 - 07/2016

**Technical Writer II** 

Amazon

Wrote internal feature announcements and task-oriented procedure guides for warehouse employees.

03/2015 - 09/2015

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

**Charter Communications** 

Worked collaboratively with video-on-demand and networking engineers to write standard procedures. Wrote Python scripts for system administration tasks.

01/2014 - 10/2014

**Technical Writer** 

SolidFire, a NetApp company

Wrote release notes, configuration and troubleshooting guides, white papers, and solution briefs for the cloud storage solution. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

12/2012 - 12/2013

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

Sybase/SAP

Wrote installation, configuration, and API guides for a mobile money app.

07/2012 - 01/2013

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

CarpeDatum

Wrote design specifications and instructor-led training guides for enterprise planning and budgeting software. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

08/2011 - 07/2012

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

Level 3 Communications, a CenturyLink company

Wrote fiber optic provisioning procedures for field technicians. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

## **Achievements**

- · Wrote shell scripts to automate API content publishing.
- Co-authored Excel 2010 in Simple Steps. ISBN: 0-27-373613-2